moneysense.ca 2011-04-22

# Rogers Publishing -- Canada’s largest publisher magazines and online

Thank you for your interest in Rogers Media products and services. We believe in giving you full disclosure about the kinds of information we gather and what we do with it, and in giving you a choice about the use of your personal information.

**General FAQs**  
_What is Rogers Media?_  
_How can I learn more about your official privacy policy?_  
_What is personal information?_  
_Does Rogers collect personal information?_  
_How does Rogers use information it gathers about me?_  
_Might I be contacted by organizations outside Rogers?_  
_What are marketing preferences?_  
_How can I change my marketing preferences?_  
_Does Rogers Media use telemarketing to sell magazine subscriptions?_  
_What if I use Rogers Cable or Wireless services?_  
_Are there other ways my information will be used?_  
_What about personalized ads in magazines?_  
_Does Rogers protect the privacy of children?_

**Web**  
_How do I unsubscribe from an e-mail newsletter?_  
_Can I change or update my e-mail newsletter subscriptions?_  
_Can I change my e-mail marketing preferences online?_  
_I'm registering on one of your sites for the first time, but my name is here already. How?_  
_Do Rogers web sites use cookies?_  
_Do Rogers websites record information about my computer or my visit?_  
_Does Rogers use "third party advertising"?_  
_What about information on public forums?_  
_What steps do you take for the security of my information?_  
_How else can I protect my privacy online?_  
_What happens to information I provide on a contest entry?_

**Contact Us**

**Rogers Privacy Policy**  

* * *

**General FAQs**

**_What is Rogers Media?_**  
Rogers Media Inc. is one of Canada's largest media enterprises, including radio stations, "Citytv", "The Shopping Channel", "Rogers Sportsnet", two multicultural television stations in Toronto, and some of Canada's best-known consumer magazines, business periodicals, directories and information products. It is part of Rogers Communications Inc, which also includes Rogers Wireless, Canada's largest wireless voice and data communications services provider, and Rogers Cable, Canada's largest cable television provider offering cable television, high-speed Internet access and video retailing.  
Back to top

_**How can I learn more about your official privacy policy?**_  
The official privacy policy commitment of our parent company, Rogers Communications Inc., can be found below in the Commitment to Privacy. A printed version can be requested. (see "Contact Us" below)  
Back to top

**_What is personal information?_**  
Personal information is any information that is related to you as an identifiable individual. It typically includes such information as your name, e-mail address, or mailing address. It could also include preferences you provided at web sites or other information.  
Back to top

**_Does Rogers collect personal information?_**  
We retain only information you provide voluntarily. We will ask for your name, address, e-mail address, or other personal information when you register with a web site or order a product or service. You may also be asked for personal information when you enter into contests or promotions sponsored by us or our partners.  
Back to top

**_How does Rogers use information it gathers about me?_**  
Rogers collects and uses your name, e-mail address and other personal information to provide you with a product or service that you requested. We may further use such information to develop and customize products or services to better meet your needs and preferences, and to offer you products and services from Rogers, including any companies within the Rogers group of companies.  
Back to top

**_Might I be contacted by organizations outside Rogers?_**  
Advertisers who use direct mail may ask Rogers Publishing to be able to send through the mail material of interest to subscribers of some of our publications, but in such cases the list is only released to a reputable third party service bureau for the purpose of sending the specific mailing. E-mail lists might be used for similar communications. All such advertising material is reviewed and subject to approval for acceptable advertising content.  
If you would prefer that you name not be provided to marketers outside of Rogers, please inform us. (see "Contact Us" below)  
Back to top

**_What are marketing preferences?_**  
In general, we assume that your relationship with Rogers Media permits us to contact you about our products and services, as well as those of our sister companies in the Rogers Group of Companies. But if you prefer otherwise, we provide clear, easy ways for you to tell us so. These are your personal marketing preferences.  
Back to top

_**How can I change my marketing preferences?**_  
You can contact a customer service representative of the Rogers Media property you receive material from, or use their online customer care (if available for that property). To access our customer care properties, please visit  
Consumer properties:http://www.rogerspublishing.ca/read_sub/CPG.shtml or  
Business to Business properties: http://www.rogerspublishing.ca/read_sub/BPPG.shtml

For consumer properties: If you registered with a password-protected profile at one of our web sites, log in to your profile update page and click the "Update Your Rogers Marketing Preferences" link at the bottom of the page. If you do not have a password-protected profile, you will have to upgrade your newsletter registration. Do this by registering for a password-protected profile with your existing e-mail address, and clicking on the upgrade link when prompted. If you prefer not to register with a password, you can remove yourself from all future marketing e-mail communications by clicking the link found at the end of any marketing e-mail.

For business to business properties: If you set up a password-protected profile at one of our web sites, log in to your profile and update your preferences. You can also remove yourself from all future marketing e-mail communications by clicking the link found at the end of any marketing e-mail.  
Back to top

_**Does Rogers Media use telemarketing to sell magazine subscriptions?**_  
Yes, we have found it convenient for some consumers to contact them by phone either to start new subscriptions or to renew an existing subscription. The authorized agents who sell new subscriptions are required to make use of the national "Do Not Call" registry so that they do not call the phone numbers of people who have registered. You can get more information about the "Do Not Call" registry here <http://www.crtc.gc.ca/eng/INFO_SHT/t1031.htm>. For telemarketing related to the renewals of existing subscriptions, you can update your contact preferences by logging in to your subscriber service page which can be found here.   
For consumer magazines: http://www.rogerspublishing.ca/read_sub/CPG.shtml[  
](http://www.rogerspublishing.ca/subscribe/subscriptions_consumer.htm)For business magazines: http://www.rogerspublishing.ca/read_sub/BPPG.shtml[](http://www.rogerspublishing.ca/subscribe/subscriptions_business.htm)  
Back to top

_**What if I use Rogers Cable or Wireless services?**_  
You should go to the customer care section of the Rogers web site at [  
http://www.rogers.com/web/Rogers.portal](http://www.rogers.com/web/Rogers.portal)  
Back to top

**_Are there other ways my information will be used?_**  
In addition to the cases above, Rogers may use your personal information when we believe in good faith that the law requires it, under circumstances specifically described to you when we collect the information (such as in a Terms of Service or Use agreement), or in the rules of sweepstakes or other promotions.   
Back to top

_**What about personalized ads in magazines?**_  
Occasionally an advertiser may ask that we print the name of subscribers in their advertisement in our publications. When this is done, the subscriber's name is printed on the ad at the same time that the mailing label is printed on the cover of the magazine, and the subscriber's name appears only in their personal copy of the magazine. If you would prefer not have your name included in such advertisements, please contact us at Magazine Subscriber Service and specify 'Do Not Personalize'.

Please note ‘Do Not Personalize’ is not applicable to business magazines.  
Back to top

_**Does Rogers protect the privacy of children?**_  
The privacy of children is important to us. We will not knowingly send direct mailings, e-mail or other correspondence to anyone who indicates that they are younger than 16 years. Your children should always ask you for permission before sending personal information to Rogers Communications Inc., or to anyone else. Any personal information we gather from children under the age of 16 would be used solely for demographic purposes.   
Back to top

* * *

**Web**

_**How do I unsubscribe from an e-mail newsletter?**_  
Every time we send out one of our newsletters, we include an "unsubscribe" link. Simply click on this link and follow the instructions. You will be automatically removed from that newsletter distribution list.   
Back to top

**_Can I change or update my e-mail newsletter subscriptions?_**  
We have many e-mail newsletters for you choose from and realize your preferences may change over time. 

For consumer properties: If you provided a password when you subscribed, just log on - using your e-mail address and your password - and you'll be brought to your profile page. All your choices are listed here. Simply click on the options provided, and then "Update Profile." If you prefer not to register with a password, you can remove yourself from all future marketing e-mail communications by clicking the link found at the end of any marketing e-mail.

For business properties: You can set your newsletter preferences by logging in to your customer care profile through [](http://www.rogerspublishing.ca/subscribe/subscriptions_business.htm)http://www.rogerspublishing.ca/read_sub/BPPG.shtml[](http://www.rogerspublishing.ca/subscribe/subscriptions_business.htm). You can also remove yourself by clicking the ‘Unsubscribe’ link found in any e-mail newsletter.  
Back to top

_**Can I change my e-mail marketing preferences online?**_   
If you registered with a password-protected profile at one of our web sites, log in to your profile update page and click the "Update Your Rogers Marketing Preferences" link at the bottom of the page. If you do not have a password-protected profile, you can upgrade your newsletter registration. Do this by registering for a password-protected profile with your existing e-mail address, and clicking on the upgrade link when prompted. If you prefer not to upgrade, you can click the link to no longer receive marketing messages at the end of any marketing e-mail.  
Back to top

_**I'm registering on one of your sites for the first time, but my name is here already. How?**_  
Virtually all Rogers Media Web sites will begin using a shared web registration service in 2006. Any information you provide at registration for a site is tied to your e-mail address. If you use the same e-mail address to register at another Rogers Media Web site, the associated information will be retrieved, so you don't have to re-enter it.  
Back to top

**_Do Rogers web sites use cookies?_**  
Yes, some Rogers web sites use cookies. Typically, a cookie is set when you register on our sites.   
A cookie is a small text file sent to your browser's files for our reference. No one else can read this file. Cookies allow our server computer to recognize you when you return to our sites, so you don't have to re-register and so we can retain any preferences you may have given us. If you do not wish to receive cookies, most browsers allow you to be alerted when a cookie is sent to your computer, so you can decide whether to accept it.  
Back to top

**_Do Rogers websites record information about my computer or my visit?_**  
Rogers collects IP addresses and related information for the purposes of system administration and to create aggregate statistical reports for advertisers. This information cannot identify you personally.

Browser information (i.e. the URL of the web page you were just on, the IP address of the computer you are using, your domain type, and your browser version) is automatically recorded as part of transmitting information over the Internet. We may use it to help us display information in the best format for you. 

We may develop summary reports for advertisers, to help them better understand our audience and provide advertisements that are more likely to be of interest to you. For example, we may report total number of visitors to our site in general or to specific pages, average length of visit, etc. No identifying data about individuals is reported.   
During your visit to our sites, we may record choices you have made and use this to provide more customized content or advertising. The data does not identify you and is not retained after your visit. This is sometimes called "clickstream" data.  
Back to top

**_Does Rogers use "third party advertising"?_**  
The ads appearing on many of the Rogers Media Web sites are delivered to you using online advertising networks. Information about your visits to this site, such as number of times you have viewed an ad or visits to certain pages of Rogers Media web sites (but not your name, address, e-mail address or other personal information) is used to serve ads to you. The ad network providers use cookies, web beacons, or similar technologies on your computer to help present, better target, and measure the effectiveness of the advertisements served to you on Rogers Media web sites or through affiliate advertising network providers. Web beacons utilize JavaScript code and write information to cookies, which are small files on your computers.  If you do not want a cookie to be written, simply change the setting in your browser.  For more information and how to "opt-out" from DoubleClick cookies, please [click here](http://www.doubleclick.com/us/about_doubleclick/privacy). For more information on how to opt-out from other ad network providers’ cookies, please [click here](http://www.jellycloud.com/optout_landing.html).  
Back to top

**_What about information on public forums?_**  
Rogers sites may make chat rooms, forums, message boards and/or news groups available to its users. Please remember that any information that is disclosed in these areas becomes public information and you should exercise caution when deciding to disclose your personal information.  
Back to top

**_What steps do you take for the security of my information?_**   
Our sites use industry-standard security measures to protect data against loss, misuse and interception by third parties. Our security policies are periodically reviewed and enhanced as necessary. However, Rogers assumes no liability for interception, alteration or misuse of information transmitted over the Internet.  
Back to top

_**How else can I protect my privacy online?**_  
Generally speaking, whenever you disclose personal information online there is a risk that the information may be intercepted, collected and used. That goes for information disclosed on message boards, in chat areas - or even in e-mail. Rogers is not responsible if that information is intercepted. You transmit information to anyone at your own risk. 

Co-branded sites and third party Internet sites and services may be accessible through Rogers sites. Third parties may collect information for their own contests or promotions, and may have their own privacy and data collection practices. Rogers is not responsible for and bears no liability for these policies or actions. 

You alone are responsible for keeping passwords and information safe. Be careful and responsible whenever you're online.  
Back to top

**_What happens to information I provide on a contest entry?_**  
Rogers uses a variety of contests and similar promotions to increase awareness of our products and services. We generally request contact information so that we can notify you if you are a prize winner. As well, in some cases we may contact contest entrants with product information. Contest entries generally include a way for you to indicate that you do not want to be contacted based on the information on your entry. Because contests may involve co-sponsors outside Rogers who have their own privacy practices, it is always advisable to read the entry form and contest rules before entering.  
Back to top

* * *

**Contact Us**

**General Inquiries**  
If you have any questions about these Rogers Media Privacy FAQs, the privacy practices of our web sites, or your dealings with us, please contact: 

Rogers Media Web Customer Care  
One Mount Pleasant Road, 8th Floor  
Toronto, ON M4Y 2Y5  

**Customers of Rogers Cable and Rogers Wireless**  
You can have your name marked "Do Not Contact" by contacting a customer service representative at the phone number listed on their invoice.

**Subscribers to Rogers Media consumer magazines**  
Notices about "Subscriber Services" that appear in each consumer magazine explain how to change your "Mail Preference" for receiving mailings from other organizations. To have your mailing address excluded from mailings by other organizations, provide your subscriber information in one of the following ways:

E-mail: | [rmpublishing@indas.ca](mailto:rmpublishing@indas.ca) (please put "Privacy" in the subject line)   
---|---  
Mail:  | Privacy Request  
Magazine Subscriber Services  
Box 860  
Markham, ON L3P 8H8  
Telephone:  | 905-946-0084   
Fax:  | 905-946-1679  
  
**Subscribers to Rogers Media Business to Business, Trade and Professional magazines**  
Each magazine’s masthead contains contact information for our Subscriber Services. To have your mailing address excluded from mailings by other organizations, provide your subscriber information in one of the following ways:

E-mail: |   
---|---  
Mail:  | Privacy Request  
Circulation Department  
PO Box 720, Station K  
Toronto, ON  M4P 3J6  
Telephone:  | 866-236-0608  
Fax:  | 416-932-1620  
  
**Privacy Policy Inquiries**  
For information about the Rogers Communications Inc. Commitment to Privacy, please contact:

Chief Privacy Officer  
Rogers Communications Inc.  
333 Bloor Street East  
Toronto, ON M4W 1G9

Back to top

* * *

_**What is the Rogers Privacy Policy?**_

The Rogers Group of Companies (Rogers) Commitment to Privacy

  1. This policy applies to Rogers Communications, Rogers Cable, Rogers Wireless and Rogers Media which are referred to here collectively as Rogers. At Rogers, the security and integrity of our customers' personal information is important to us. We take every reasonable measure necessary to protect the privacy of our customers while providing the high level communication services they expect. 
  2. Rogers' privacy practices are in accordance with all federal and provincial laws and regulations. We are compliant with the Personal Information Protection and Electronic Documents Act (PIPEDA) and where applicable with the privacy rules established by the Canadian Radio-television and Telecommunications Commission (CRTC). 
  3. Rogers has in place privacy and security practices to safeguard our customers’ personal information. These practices are reviewed, and if necessary revised, on a regular basis. Additionally, Rogers' employees receive privacy training and must comply with Rogers' privacy practices as a condition of employment. 
  4. Personal information collected by Rogers is information about an identifiable individual that may include such information as your name, e-mail address, mailing address, phone number, financial information, birth date and any recorded complaints. 
  5. At Rogers, we collect customer information for one or more of the following purposes: 
  6. Rogers does not use or disclose personal information for purposes other than those for which it was collected, except with the consent of the individual or as required by law. Rogers retains personal information only as long as necessary for the fulfillment of those purposes. 
  7. Rogers informs customers of the existence, use and disclosure of their personal information upon request and gives them access to their information. 
  8. Rogers ensures that customer information is accurate, complete and up-to-date. Customers can challenge the accuracy and completeness of the information and request amendments as appropriate. 
  9. Rogers companies share information with other Rogers companies or their agents and authorized dealers, in order to offer customers products and services that they may find attractive. Notices on sharing information are contained in each company's application forms, invoices and web sites. If customers do not want to be marketed with these products and services, they can contact Rogers (see How To Contact Rogers below). 
  10. Additional information on your privacy is located in the Frequently Asked Questions section of [www.rogers.com](http://www.rogers.com/) under the Category of Privacy. 
  11. A senior company officer has been appointed as the Privacy Officer at Rogers. The Privacy Officer is accountable for all personal information at Rogers. You may contact the Privacy Officer at: 

By Mail: Chief Privacy Officer  
Rogers Communications Inc.   
333 Bloor Street East  
Toronto, ON M4W 1G9   
By E-mail: [privacy@rci.rogers.com](mailto:privacy@rci.rogers.com)

  12. Customers that wish to:  may contact a Rogers customer service representative who, if necessary, will refer the customer to the Rogers Privacy Officer. 
  13. The Office of the Privacy Commissioner of Canada oversees Rogers' personal information handling practices. If your privacy concerns are not addressed to your satisfaction by Rogers you may contact the Office of the Privacy Commissioner of Canada for further guidance: 

By Phone: 1-800-282-1376 or 613-995-8210  
By Fax: 613-947-6850   
By E-mail: [info@privcom.gc.ca](mailto:info@privcom.gc.ca)  
Website: [www.privcom.gc.ca](http://www.privcom.gc.ca/)

Back to top

**How to Contact Rogers**   
_Customers of Rogers Cable and Rogers Wireless_  
Customers can have their account marked "Do Not Contact" by visiting Rogers On-line Self Service at [www.rogers.com](http://www.rogers.com/) and selecting “Manage My Marketing Permissions” under “Your On-line Profile” or click here to opt-out. Alternatively, you can contact a Rogers' customer service representative at 1-888-899-1188. 

_Subscribers to Rogers Media consumer magazines_  
Notices about "Subscriber Services" that appear in each consumer magazine explain how to change your "Mail Preference" for receiving mailings from other organizations. To have your mailing address excluded from mailings by other organizations, provide your subscriber information in one of the following ways: 

E-mail: | [rmpublishing@indas.ca](mailto:rmpublishing@indas.ca)  
---|---  
Mail:  | Privacy Request  
Magazine Subscriber Services  
Box 860  
Markham, ON L3P 8H8  
Telephone:  | 905-946-0084   
Fax:  | 905-946-1679  
  
_Registered users of Rogers Media web sites and e-mail newsletters_   
You can update your e-mail communication preferences that are part of your profile. Click on "log in" and provide your e-mail address and password. If you have forgotten your password, you can request a replacement. 

**Rogers.com Privacy Policy**

Rogers.com has created this Privacy Policy in order to demonstrate our firm commitment to privacy. The following discloses our information gathering and dissemination practices for this Web site. 

We use your IP address to help diagnose problems with our server, and to administer our Web site. Your IP address is also used to gather broad, aggregated demographic information. Our site may use cookies to make sure you don't see the same ad repeatedly. We use cookies to deliver content specific to your interests, to save your password so you don't have to re-enter it each time you visit our site, and for the other purposes set out below: 

  * We use cookies to remind us who you are and to find your account information in our database when you access a service so you do not need to log in at every visit. This helps us to provide you with service tailored to your specific needs and interests. A cookie is created when you register for a service. 
  * We use cookies to estimate our audience size. Your browser is given a unique cookie that helps us determine whether yours is a repeat visit or a first visit. 
  * We use cookies to determine the browser the visitor uses so the site can be designed to work properly with the most common versions of different browsers. 
  * Advertisers that place ads with Rogers.com may use cookies 

Our site's registration forms require users to give us a unique username and password. To post a message in [www.rogers.com](http://www.rogers.com/) using an e-form, an email address is also required. 

This site contains links to third party sites. Rogers.com is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such Web sites. Rogers.com co-branded sites and content partner sites may have privacy policies independent of Rogers.com. This Privacy Policy extends only to data collected on pages hosted on Rogers.com servers. Rogers.com may share aggregate information with trading partners, co-branded sites, and advertisers. However, this aggregated information does not contain personally identifiable information. 

Our online surveys and the contests on our site may ask visitors for such information as contact information (like their email address), financial information (like their investment portfolio holdings), and demographic information (like their postal code, age or income level). We may use contact data from our surveys or contests to send information about our company and promotional material from some of our partners, sponsors or advertisers. The customer's contact information may also be used to contact the visitor when necessary and may be shared with other affiliated companies within the Rogers Group of Companies who may want to contact our visitors. Only the Rogers Group of Companies has access to your personal information. Users may opt-out of receiving future e-mail communications. Please see the choice/opt-out section below. 

Demographic and profile data is used to tailor our visitor's experience at our site and display the content according to their preferences. This information is shared with advertisers on an aggregate basis only. 

**Public Forums**   
This site makes chat rooms, forums, message boards and/or news groups available to its users. Please remember that any information that is disclosed in these areas becomes public information and you should exercise caution when deciding to disclose your personal information. 

**Security**   
This site has reasonable security measures in place to protect against loss, misuse and interception by third parties. The Rogers Group of Companies assumes no liability for interception, alteration or misuse of information transmitted over the Internet. 

**Children's Guidelines**   
This site is not marketed to or directed towards children. Nevertheless, it is possible for children to publicly post or distribute personally identifiable contact information without prior parental consent within chat rooms, forums, message boards, and/or news groups. No communication, however, will be sent to anyone or information collected from anyone who indicates that they are younger than 16 years old without their parents' permission. 

**Choice/Opt-Out**   
In the Registration process where we request information about the visitor, our site provides users the opportunity to opt-out of receiving email or other forms of communications from the Rogers Group of Companies. 

If you are here because you no longer want to be contacted by the Rogers Group of Companies please [click here to opt-out](https://www.shoprogers.com/newsletter/opt_out.asp). 

**Contacting Us**   
If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, the practices of this site, or your dealings with this web site, you can contact:   
  
By Mail: Chief Privacy Officer  
Rogers Communications Inc.  
333 Bloor Street East  
Toronto, ON M4W 1G9 

By E-mail: [privacy@rci.rogers.com](mailto:privacy@rci.rogers.com)Back to top
